hey barbecue fans jb here with barton
barbecue smokeworks hope everybody's
doing well out there
um we are answering the mail bag today
and we've got an inquiry from one of our
viewers
michelle k writes hey jb while we love
using our grill in the backyard
we would appreciate more information on
the grill grates
we're unfamiliar with this product and
would like to learn more about them
so well you're in luck michelle kay
because here's a nice little video
highlighting the grill grates and their
uses
and it's a great little addition to your
barbecue arsenal i hope you find it
useful
and as always guys if you find this
informational
hit the subscribe button below and give
us a thumbs up we appreciate it we're
we're still an infant channel and trying
to
grow a fan base and we appreciate you
taking the time out of your day to watch
a video
all righty the grill grates so they make
these in different sizes
and just about for every grill out there
if you don't see one size for your pit
you can have
them custom cut the cool thing about
these
is they they evenly conduct heat it's a
great piece of alloy
it protects against flare-ups and
virtually rules out hot and cold spots
because it dissipates
the heat in between
the sets typically come in three to four
pieces and they're easily assembled
once you follow the included
instructions on how to season them
you're good to go ready to fire the pit
up
you can use these on charcoal grills gas
grills
komodo grills fire pits
anything you have that you typically
grill on you can use these on
the cool thing is each set comes with a
custom spatula too that fits perfect
down in the valleys
so you can protect your seared food
edges by picking it up from underneath
disassembly and cleaning is also simple
and efficient
and they don't take up much room at all
to store
so maybe you're not wanting grill grate
marks on your food
well you can take this and flip it over
upside down
opposite the way your grill is running
and use it as a hot plate works great
for smash burgers or searing veggies or
whatever you may want to cook on a flat
top
steaks are the protein that put this
product on the map but you can cook
anything on them chicken
fish veggies anything that you can grill
can be cooked on these grates
the booklet that comes along with this
set has a ton of information in it it
tells you how to season the grates how
to set up for two zone grilling
how to clean them
and it's full of recipes as well so they
get you
started right out of the box as soon as
you seize them you're ready to cook
thanks for following along today and
hopefully you
have hit the subscribe button and the
thumbs up button we appreciate it
um check out our links below we
typically
reference all of the products we utilize
in our videos
in links below so they're easy for you
to find and leave a comment
we appreciate it thank you
[Music]
you